Kristin Brewer

SPEECH-LANGUAGE PATHOLOGIST

Professional Profile

Well-rounded health care professional that has worked as a Speech-Language Pathologist skilled in therapy practices for both adults and children in various medical settings. Creative, compassionate, people-oriented individual who is experienced in working in fast-paced environments demanding strong organization and interpersonal skills.

330.827.4032



kristinkrussell@yahoo.com



Charlottesville, VA



Education

MASTER OF SCIENCE Communication Sciences and Disorders East Carolina University 2013

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE Hearing, Speech and Language Sciences Ohio University 2010

Certifications

Certificate of Clinical Competence
American Speech Hearing
Association
2014-current

Virginia Board of Speech-Language
Pathology and Audiology
2013-current

American Heart Association BLS Provider (adult/children)

Yoga Alliance RYT-200

Professional Experience

Speech Therapy Department Team Lead, Speech-Language Pathologist (Full-time)

UVA Encompass Health Rehabilitation Hospital

August 2018-July 2022

Engagement

- Championed interdisciplinary patient care and set the standard of increased communication and teamwork between departments.
- Served on CEO Council to interact with hospital leadership to identify and create solutions for optimizing patient experience, hospital culture, and business acumen.
- Coordinated and facilitated monthly educational meetings related to evidence-based practice related to interdisciplinary clinical practice of individuals with CVAs.
- Coordinated and facilitated employee engagement activities such as fitness challenges, holiday activities and kindness cards.
- Acted as co-chair of community Aphasia Support Group including coordination of facility, speakers, and member management.
- Member of Stroke Comeback Club that provides community outreach and support for individuals that are post-stroke.
- Embarked on individual leadership development and initiated education and implementation of improved leadership within therapy department.
- Participated in hospital sponsored events including American Heart Association Heart and Stroke walks and fundraiser events.

Development

- Led hospital transition from National Dysphagia Diet (NDD) to the International Dysphagia Diet Standardization Initiative (IDDSI) through presentation in-person multidisciplinary staff education with ongoing competency classes.
- Developed and acted as chairwoman of interdisciplinary Dementia Committee within hospital allowing for education and better care practices for patients with dementia to meet needs of shifting demographics.
- Developed educational material for regional company distribution and implementation related to care for individuals with dementia.
- Acted as a professional mentor for staff and provided supervision for graduate students during clinical placements.
- Created digital educational tools for onboarding new staff to allow for increased independence and confidence with documentation.
- Led yearly education for physicians and residents about speech therapy roles in inpatient rehabilitation and IDDSI.

Clinical

- Completed thorough evaluation and treatment interventions for adults with speech, language, swallow, and cognitive disorders in inpatient rehabilitation setting.
- Completed Langmore Foundation FEES course began mentorship for clinical practice of passing Fiberoptic Endoscopic Evaluation of Swallowing (FEES).
- Coordinated information, created, and presented material during review of JACHO Stroke Certification for hospital.
- Advocated for patients in COVID isolation, facilitating use of iPads to supplement and support social isolation.

Professional Development

- ASHA Member
- Langmore Foundation FEES Course
- CPI Dementia Capable Care Trainor Certification
- VitalStim
- ASHA Special Interest Groups: Neurogenic Communication Disorders, Gerontology

Personal Interest

- Enjoying time with my dog
- Photography and photoshop
- Hatha Yoga
- Event and travel planning

- Performed detailed monthly chart audits to ensure care validity and accuracy of hospital documentation.
- Managed clinical team of SLPs in inpatient rehabilitation setting to ensure compliance with best therapy practice, personal development, and business expectations.

Speech-Language Pathologist (Full-time)

Chesapeake Retirement Community, RehabCare August 2017-December 2018

- Conducted screens and evaluations related to speech, language, and swallowing disorders.
- Created and implemented individualized treatment plans to address varied speech, language, and swallowing deficits.
- Worked in tandem with various disciplines, caregivers, and staff to provide and implement individualized care for patients.
- Consistently completed thorough and timely documentation to allow for appropriate communication with medical personnel and for reimbursement purposes.

Speech-Language Pathologist (Full-time)

Walnut Hills Retirement Community, HealthPro

September 2016-June 2017

- Demonstrated social and professional competencies within culturally diverse setting.
- Managed adult caseload given a continuum of care community including outpatient, short-term rehabilitation and long-term care.
- Completed screening, evaluation, and treatment for adults through geriatric patients addressing a variety of diagnosis such as dysphagia, aphasia, and motor speech disorders.
- Developed relationships with various staff within the community to promote best practice for comprehensive patient care.

Speech-Language Pathologist (Full-time)

Coshocton County Memorial Hospital

December 2015-September 2016

- Administered and interpreted instrumental, standardized, and informal assessment of adults and children with cognitive, neurogenic, motor speech and swallowing impairments within an acute care and outpatient setting.
- Created and implemented individualized treatment plans for adults and children with cognitive, neurogenic, voice motor speech, and swallowing impairments in acute care and outpatient setting.
- Responsible for child language evaluations to determine appropriateness for Augmentative Alternative Communication Devices and provided patient/family/educator in-services on device use and implementation for daily use.
- Managed high-paced and varied caseload split between inpatient and outpatient hospital setting.

Speech-Language Pathologist (Full-time) Virginia Health Rehab Agency

June 2013-November 2015

- Conducted formal and informal assessments of swallowing, voice, cognition, speech, and language in skilled nursing facility and outpatient clinic.
- Created and implemented individualized treatment of swallowing, cognitive, motorspeech, and language disorders for individuals with acute and complex medical diagnoses.
- Assessed oral motor function, swallowing, speech and language skills of children in outpatient setting using diverse testing batteries.
- Prepared and delivered individualized treatment of speech sound disorders and language disorders for typically developing children and those with mild to severe developmental disabilities.
- Provided in-services to families and staff for essential patient care including aspiration precautions, oral hygiene, and feeding strategies.